

Cra. 63 #33 - 60 Medellín - Colombia

(+57) 316 8261836

j.cruz@ieee.org

ABOUT ME

I am a person that has maths and algorithms in his mind and who is a faithful practitioner of the Continuous innovation process. I specialize in data architecture and data analytics. I have great expertise in the Splunk Software and Python at applying ML concepts of Analytics to Industrial Internet Of Things.

SKILLS

WORK

PROGRAMMING
PYTHON
ANALYTICS
MATHEMATICS
MACHINE LEARNING

PERSONAL

RESPONSABILITY
ORGANIZATION
TEAM PLAYER
HONESTY
CREATIVITY

JESUS ANDRES CRUZ SANABRIA

ELECTRONIC ENGINEER

EXPERIENCE

(2017 – present)

DATA ENGINEER SSR.

SUMMAN SAS

I am Planning and deployment of infrastructure requirements, configuration processes of operating systems for data analytics activities, data policies, data extraction method definitions, and administration guidelines for operations. I am to apply knowledge regarding data mining, data processing, data modeling, description analytics and predictive analytics using supervised and unsupervised ML algorithms.

(2016 - 2017)

DEVELOPER JR.

PITMMAM SAS

I developed and implemented Digital Image Processing for face recognition in python. I Supported cloud web service. I Developed python integrations for desktop and web applications.

(2015 - 2016)

DEVELOPER JR.

MASSEQ SAS

I developed and supported web services for mining sector.

EDUCATION

(2009 - 2017)

BACHELOR OF ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING

UNIVERSIDAD SURCOLOMBIANA

Grade project: System design for drowsiness detection and prediction with EEG Digital Signal processing and Machine Learning

SPLUNK CERTIFIED ARCHITECT

SPLUNK EDUCATION

License N°: Cert-281350

AWARDS

- Winner in ethics competition in XIV National Meeting Branch IEEE Colombia in 2015
- Elect Chair for 2018-2019 in IEEE Medellín Subsection in 2018